Tyler Minegar

Senior Software Engineer

About Me

Full Stack Developer with 8+ years of experience on modern Frontend and Backend Web Developements.

Consulting basic business models, realized pixel-pefect design, implemented scalable & maintainable components with clear requirements.

Highly experienced, solutions-oriented professional in overseeing all aspects of the SDLC from extensive analysis and design through deployments and maintenance, Agile environment, DevOps and Team collaboration.

Creative, Result-Focused, Passionate & Self-Learner. Keep Curious and ahead about new technologies.

☑ Email

tylerminegar.dev@gmail.com

Phone

Address

+1 908 628 0718

907, Huff Ave, Manvile, NJ, 08835,

USA

Professional Skills

C#



Work Experience

Software Engineer, Full Stack at Keyavi

Oct, 2021 - Present

Keyavi provides studios and creators with policy-based control that allows them to protect their business assets with end-to-end enforceable restrictions over users, locations, time access, and more.

- Design, build, and maintain efficient, reusable, and reliable software solutions employing API frameworks, .NET libraries & applications including .NET MAUI, and Azure cloud services.
- Develop and deliver future versions of Keyavi platform services including those designed for modern cloud deployments, REST / GraphQL APIs and microservices for application and platform integration.
- Support the development of mission critical features & functions by helping translate business requirements and use cases for new cybersecurity services into technical design, functional applications and secure, scalable deployments. Review, test, and verify code for adherence to quality and security standards
- Continually invest in personal learning, technical growth, process improvements and team cohesion to become a strong contributing member of Keyavi.

Azure ASP.NET C# React

Full Stack Developer at GovTact

Nov, 2019 - Sep, 2021

GovTact supports IT infrastructure and application modernization for multiple government and commercial partners, ensuring mission readiness and operational security.

- Work on the front line of the research, development, design, and deployment of a state of the art visualization tool that taps into enterprise-level data sources that will revolutionize the way our customer interacts with their data.
- Responsible for designing, testing, coding, and developing solutions to meet customer needs; ensuring software continues to function normally through software maintenance, upgrade, and testing; documenting the application, service and environment as a reference for future operations and maintenance, including version and platform upgrades
- Develop in an AWS cloud environment using cutting edge technology.

AWS C# ASP.NET Javascript

.NET Full Stack Developer at eTranService

May, 2017 - Oct, 2019

eTranService anticipates and adapt to a changing world by transforming advanced technologies into value for our clients through professional solutions, services, and a process-driven workforce.

- Create or modify applications based on direction from the Software Architect.
- Work with Software Architect to determine level of effort required for a feature, user story, or task.
- Work with Data Management team to ensure successful cloud data structure/access for migrated applications.
- Assist in evaluating applications/tools readiness level for Cloud environments.

C# ASP.NET Kanban React

Education

2013 - 2017

Bachelor's degree of Computer and Information Engineering from University of Cambridge